For many, the idea of commuting daily to a place of work might sound outdated.
对许多人而言，每日通勤上班的想法或许已过时。
In the UK, at least, the shape of the working week is changing, and a new hybrid approach is becoming commonplace.
至少在英国，工作周的模式正在改变，一种全新的混合办公模式正变得普遍。
This new look seems inevitable: new technology means tasks traditionally done in the office can be done at home.
这种新趋势看似不可避免：新技术意味着传统上在办公室完成的工作也能在家实现。
And there's the demand for a better work-life balance, too.
人们也愈发追求更好的工作与生活平衡。
All of this has been accelerated by the necessary changes brought on by the Covid pandemic.
新冠疫情带来的必要变革，更是加速了这一切。
One obvious change in the UK is that Friday has become the most popular day to work from home.
英国一个明显的变化是，周五已成为最受欢迎的居家办公日。
One survey found it's when just 13% of workers go into the office.
一项调查发现，仅有13%的员工会在周五去办公室。
It means employees can save on commuting costs and the price of lunches.
这意味着员工能节省通勤成本和午餐费用。
And Claire McCartney from The Chartered Institute of Personnel and Development told the BBC that generally employers thought the shift to hybrid working and home working had "increased productivity rather than decreased it".
英国特许人事与发展协会的克莱尔·麦卡特尼接受BBC采访时表示，总体而言，雇主认为转向混合办公和居家办公“提高了而非降低了工作效率”。
Monday is also becoming a 'work from home' day: a recent study of mobile phone activity in the UK suggested a typical week in the office now runs from Tuesday to Thursday.
周一也逐渐成为“居家办公日”：英国一项针对手机使用情况的最新研究表明，如今典型的办公室办公周为周二至周四。
This means companies have to think differently about the workspace they provide.
这意味着企业必须重新思考所提供的办公空间。
Mark Allan, chief executive of property firm LandSec, told the BBC: "We certainly believe there are going to be fewer people in offices for the longer term, and we are planning accordingly."
房地产公司LandSec的首席执行官马克·艾伦接受BBC采访时表示：“我们坚信，长期来看，办公室的办公人数会减少，我们也在据此制定规划。”
A shorter office week isn't great news for the city-centre shops, which depend on trade from workers.
办公周缩短对依赖上班族客流的市中心商铺而言并非好消息。
But suburban and small-town high streets are reporting an increase in footfall as people work and shop locally.
但随着人们居家办公、就近购物，郊区和小镇商业街的客流量有所上升。
There's also an emerging trend for a shorter working week.
如今还出现了缩短工作周的新趋势。
Some companies are experimenting with a four-day working week – but with the same full-time pay.
一些企业正在试行四天工作制——但薪资保持全职标准。
They have tried to make work time more efficient by cutting out unnecessary meetings and having shorter breaks, for example.
例如，他们通过取消不必要的会议、缩短休息时间来提高工作效率。
They claim this has made workers more productive.
企业称这一举措提升了员工的工作效率。
All this makes you wonder if the act of going to work and doing the nine-to-five will become a thing of the past.
这一切不禁让人思考，朝九晚五上班的模式是否会成为历史。